Be careful who you let in.
The Guest is a mystery, thriller, action film directed by Adam Wingard.
A soldier introduces himself to the Peterson family, claiming
to be a friend of their son who died in action.
After the young man is welcomed into their home, a series of
accidental deaths seem to be connected to his presence.
"David", played by Dan Stevens.
Anna Peterson, played by Maika Monroe.
Luke Peterson, played by Brendan Meyer.
Laura Peterson, played by Sheila Kelley.
Spencer Peterson, played by Leland Orser.
Major Carver, played by Lance Reddick.
The Guest is a 2014 American action thriller film directed by
Adam Wingard and written by Simon Barrett.
The film stars Dan Stevens and Maika Monroe, with a supporting cast that includes
Leland Orser, Sheila Kelley, Brendan Meyer, and Lance Reddick.
It tells the story of a U.S.
soldier (Stevens) called David who unexpectedly visits the Peterson family,
introducing himself as a friend of their son who died in combat in Afghanistan.
After he has been staying in their home for a couple of days, a series of deaths
occur, and the daughter Anna (Monroe) suspects David is connected to them.
Barrett, who previously worked with Wingard on the films A Horrible Way to Die
(2010) and You're Next (2011), wrote the script for The Guest.
Budgeted at $5 million, filming took place in New
Mexico during the summer of 2013.
Musician Steve Moore scored the film's soundtrack.
The film premiered at the Sundance Film Festival on January 17, 2014, and was
theatrically released in the United States on September 17.
The Guest received generally positive reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of high school,
psychopath, harassment, halloween, diner.
The tone is intense and mind_bending.